Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
You saved her life.
Give me a blanket!
I told you not to go!
You'll stay in the hold!
I don't wanna see you
until we reach Marseille.
What's wrong?
You think I'm harsh?
I know I am. I take pride in that.
Go!
Come on. everyone to your stations!
Put her somewhere dry
before she freezes to death.
Wait!
Go!
Sleep well?
You have something that belongs to me.
I've never seen
the Emperor's handwriting before.
Give me back that letter.
I don't think so.
What do you want?
A good reason not to turn you in.
Try money.
It usually works.
I don't have any.
But I have friends.
If you say anything
about this letter to anyone.
they will find you and they will kill you.
Captain Danglars.
Sir?
I've caused you a lot of trouble.
I don't know how to thank you.
You just did.
Take care.
Miss...
Angéle.
Edmond.
I'll never forget your courage.
but you must forget my name.
Goodbye. Edmond.
Goodbye. Angéle.
Morrel wants to see you.
We had changed the watch.
We were off Cap Corse.
The swells were strong.
We were 200 fathoms from the wreck.
Give me the Captain's log.
We started kicking around the debris
when Dantés tried
to take the longboat out.
I told him not to.
It was a foolish thing to do.
Is that true?
Yes. sir. Except it wasn't foolish.
we'd do it for any of our crew.
- It was my decision! I ordered...
- I took charge--
...to turn the ship around. and he dove in.
You dove.
Captain Danglars
didn't say I couldn't dive.
That's enough!
Did you see that insolence?
Mr. Morrel. I'm telling you.
this boy is out of control.
I don't want to sail with him.
You won't sail with him anymore.
See. I warned you.
Because you'll never sail for me again.
Excuse me?
How could you let a woman drown?
I saved your shipment. Mr. Morrel.
And Dantés saved my honor. Danglars.
- Captain Danglars.
- You're no longer captain.
Go and pack your things.
I'll have your pay settled.
We don't even know who that woman is.
I know what you did.
and that's all I need to know.
Hey. little guy. come here!
Come!
Now. let that be a lesson to you. okay?
When you're a man. you don't hide
behind your rank or under a table.
Edmond. this is my grandson. Maximilian.
Nice to meet you. Maximilian.
Maximilian. this is Captain Dantés.
- Hello. Captain.
- So. how old--
Captain?
Yes. Try to prove yourself worthy. Edmond.
Of course. sir. Of course.
Good boy.
Edmond!
- I can't believe you're here!
- I...
- I have to tell you something.
- That you love me.
- Yes. of course. but--
- No buts.
- Wait. but--
- You're doing it again!
You're kissing a future captain.
- You?
- Yes.
- That means we can--
- Yes. we can.
I missed you.
I missed you so much.
See you later.
- Edmond! Edmond.
- Juliette.
- How are you?
- And you?
Yes. I'm fine.
It's Edmond. Louis' son!
- Good morning. sir.
- Good morning.
Where's my father? I have to see him.
- At home.
- See you later.
Smile a little. It's good news.
You look sad.
It's joy.
I'm so proud of you!
Captain!
Captain.
Did you tell Mr. and Mrs. de Morcerf?
No. not yet. I wanted to tell you first.
Everything will change. Dad.
We have to tell them.
This is thanks to them.
And to you too.
I didn't pay for you to go to Navy School.
Go on. Son.
go pay your respects.
How about a toast?
I raise my glass
to the memory of your mother. Edmond.
First. because we miss her
and because she gave birth
to Marseille's youngest captain!
- Bravo!
- Yes. go ahead.
Clap. it will make him uncomfortable.
That's it. Perfect.
But most of all. because Mathilde Dantés
looked after a future French nobleman
with a heroic destiny.
One of Europe's most handsome officers.
I'm speaking of Fernand de Morcerf.
at your service.
Louis!
Come and toast to the occasion.
Thank you. sir. Maybe later.
Please. scold Mercedes for me.
She doesn't listen to me anymore.
You'll see.
she'll be late for her own wedding.
Oh! Finally!
I'm sorry I'm late. Auntie!
Oh! Hello. Uncle.
Horace had a mind of his own.
I was this close to giving him a spanking.
- Mercédés!
- Mr. Count.
- Who is this gentleman?
- No. it's a horse. Mom.
But he's from a good family.
- Hello. Cousin.
- Edmond.
- Mercédés.
I hope you're ready to party.
our Edmond has some great news for you.
Yes.
Yes. I'm going to be a captain.
Captain of the Pharaoh. It's official.
Really?
- Congratulations.
- To the captain!
Got it.
To your health!
I'm really happy for you. my friend.
Yes. I'm really happy
for me too. my friend.
- Cheers!
- You're getting a new uniform?
And more importantly. a new paycheck.
He'll finally be able to enjoy life.
have a good time.
And we'll show him how it's done.
And I'll be able to get married.
- What's this about?
- You're going to be my witness.
- Don't count on it.
- Yes.
Witness to a disaster!
M-- Mercédés. say something!
Well. I tried. But what can I do?
- He's madly in love.
- Completely mad.
- Mad. mad.
- Does she know?
I mean. is she okay with it?
- Yeah. from what she told me.
- I know!
- It's Juliette.
- Who?
- No!
- The laundry girl with the naughty eyes.
No. it's not Juliette!
No. she's... a real woman.
Very beautiful.
Not just beautiful.
- Mysterious and beguiling.
- Yes! Yes. that too.
Who is she?
It's your cousin.
Mercédés Herrera de Morcerf.
You?
- Yes!
- We're getting married. Fernand.
Are you out of your mind?
Your mother will never allow it.
Do you really think
my mother can say "no" to me?
Besides. you'll help to convince her.
You were always her favorite nephew.
Amen.
I bring. signed by Mr. de Villefort.
the King's Prosecutor.
a warrant for the arrest of Edmond Dantés.
- Come with us. sir.
- What's going on?
- No. There's got to be an explanation.
- Leave him alone.
- Come on!
- Let go of me.
- Wait.
- Fernand. do something.
What nonsense is this?
My son didn't do anything.
Sir. there must be some misunderstanding.
Where are you taking him? I'll go with you.
We have orders to take him alone. sir.
Lieutenant. Lieutenant Fernand de Morcerf.
Tell your friends to let us pass. Lieutenant.
This is a royal order.
- I'll take care of it.
- Please. come with us now. sir.
- Edmond!
- Don't worry. I'll be back. my love!
Edmond Dantés. Mr. Prosecutor.
Leave us.
I've always admired sailors like you.
Mr. Dantes.
Nothing scares me. apart from the sea.
It's an endless abyss.
With its black water.
It feels like a monster is just waiting
to come out and eat you.
What's the charge. Mr. Prosecutor?
Why was I arrested
in the middle of my wedding?
Do you have an enemy. Mr. Dantés?
An enemy?
Yes. or someone who's jealous?
You've been made captain.
You're about to marry one
of the best eligible women in the region.
Someone could be envious.
you know what people are like.
...I don't know.
I had a disagreement
with a crew member recently.
but I don't see what
he could charge me with.
I don't know.
Of being a Napoleonic agent. for example.
I beg your pardon?
T-- That doesn't make any sense.
We found this Bible in your cabin.
This is your Bible. isn't it?
It's got your name on it.
Yes. but that's not a crime.
Indeed.
But we also found
inside of it a mission order...
...signed by Napoleon himself.
And that. you see. is a crime.
Wait. wait!
No. I-- I swear.
I've never seen this letter before!
If you don't have an enemy.
who could have put it there?
Off Cap Corse.
I saved a young woman from drowning.
Did she came to your cabin to thank you?
No. But Captain Danglars locked her there.
and she didn't get out until Marseilles.
You can check.
You can ask Caderousse.
Quartermaster Gaspard Caderousse.
- He can confirm it for you.
- Caderousse?
Yes.
- What do you know about this woman?
- Nothing.
Mr. Dantés.
I've interrogated
many conspirators in my life.
I don't think you're one of them.
I'm happy to help a friend of de Morcerf.
but I need your help as well.
I swear. I don't know anything about her.
She just said her name was Angéle.
That's all.
Did you reveal
this young woman's name to anyone?
No.
Not even to Caderousse?
No. I told no one. I swear on my honor.
Well. you see. Mr. Dantés.
I believe you.
Nevertheless. I'll have
to keep you for a while longer.
while I interrogate the crew.
If he confirms your testimony.
which I'm sure he will.
I'll return you to your fiancée.
who will be delighted
blaming me for this issue.
You can count on it.
Fernand will bring him back.
- I can't take it. I'm going!
- There's nothing you can do that he can't.
You'd be happy if they imprisoned him.
How can you say
such horrible things. Mercédés?
Gérard. Whatever you've heard
about Dantés. I'll vouch for it.
Give us a moment. please. gentlemen.
Fernand. I'm so sorry about your friend.
I know you're close...
...but there's a lot you don't know.
We found an order
from the emperor on his person.
And these crewmen claim
he's one of the emperor's followers.
I think you understand
the seriousness of these accusations.
We were lucky enough to stop him
before he married Mercédés
and damaged her reputation.
But if you're willing to vouch for him.
if you think those two men are lying...
...if you're willing to take that risk.
then I'll let him go.
Just say the word.
No.
No?
He doesn't deserve it.
What doesn't he deserve?
To soil our family's name.
If Dantés betrayed us...
...what will become of him?
I can see to it...
...that no trial will tarnish
the reputation of de Morcerf.
I'm going to need you to testify.
Do you understand?
So keep your mouth shut.
Mr. Dantés.
- Were you able to talk to the prosecutor?
- Yes. sir.
This is a day I'll never forget.
I don't suppose you're taking me home.
No. we're not.
Go ahead.
Wait. what's going on? What's going on?
Let go of me! Call the prosecutor.
I've spoken with the prosecutor!
Call him! Call him!
I'm innocent! I didn't do I.
I'm innocent! Let go of me!
If you were guilty. you'd be hanged!
The only reason I'm taking you
is because you know things. so shut up.
Get up.
Stop. Stop!
Let go of me!
- Where is he?
- I couldn't do anything.
Mercédés.
Let me go.
It wouldn't do any good.
- Mercédés. please!
- Let me--
What's wrong. Victoria?
Aren't you happy to see me?
Your sister is here.
Mademoiselle de Villefort.
clandestinity agrees with you.
I'm sorry I can't return the compliment.
Cognac?
I'm sorry. I'm out of seawater.
That's right.
it's my job to know everything.
In that case. you know Dantés is innocent.
Innocent? Yes.
- Who is truly innocent these days?
- He didn't do anything.
Why did you arrest him?
To save you. What kind of question is that?
Me or your reputation?
We're both in politics.
In politics. you don't remove a man.
you remove an obstacle.
I knew how cruelly
you practiced your job as a royalist.
but I hoped you'd do it honestly.
Since you're so honest.
why don't you turn yourself in for him?
Oh. I will. Gérard.
If you won't save him. I will.
I think you'd rather
people didn't know about me.
and Victoria. your mistress.
and your unborn child.
That's what I thought.
Alive?
Alive.
Right. I-- I'm hearing...
Who... Who exactly...
Someone's there? Someone's there!
Someone's there!
Someone's there...
Someone--
Who are you?
I-- Dantés. Edmond Dantés.
How old are you?
You sound like a young man.
Ha}
I don't know.
I was 22... when they locked me up.
May 16th. 1815.
That was four years ago.
You're 26.
Four years?
And you? Who are you?
A prisoner.
Like you.
For how long?
- Hush.
- What is it?
- They're coming.
- Wait. Don't leave me.
Who are you? At least tell me your name.
- Alive?
- Your name!
Alive.
Thirty-four. alive?
I was waiting for you.
Do you really think we can get out of here?
I've dug 30 meters in six years...
to get around your cell
and reach the outside.
We'll have to dig twice as long.
Twelve years?
Maybe a little less...
now that there are two of us.
Why? Do you have other plans?
No.
I am Abbot Faria.
Edmond Dantés.
You had never seen that letter?
No. I hadn't.
And you. do you know why you're here?
Yes.
They wanted to silence you.
but they wanted me to talk.
I only confide in trusted people.
I choose whom I confide in.
You don't speak Italian?
- No.
- English. Arabic. Latin. Greek? No?
No. I only know the sea.
I could teach you. if you want.
With patience and willpower. in...
...Six or seven years.
you'll know everything I know.
History. philosophy. mathematics.
they're all weapons.
They have as much power to free you as this.
What's the first thing you'll do...
if we get out of here?
I'll find Mercédés.
What will you do if she didn't wait for you?
Then I'll have nothing left.
I'll tell you a story. Edmond.
700 years ago. in Jerusalem.
during the first Crusade...
...the knights entrusted
with protecting the tomb of Christ
created the Order of the Templars.
On the first day. there were only
a few of them. but they had great faith.
With their victories.
the order amassed a fortune.
A significant one.
Sig-- significant.
The greatest treasure
the earth has ever seen.
And...
...over time...
their power and wealth made others envious.
On Friday. October 13th. 1307.
the King of France. Philip the Bel.
orders their arrest
and confiscates their possessions.
But no one ever found the treasure.
Do you know...
...what those knights did
with that enormous fortune?
- No.
- Nothing.
Edmond. they did nothing.
They were too busy gnawing at themselves.
Punishing those who betrayed them.
They all died. one by one.
Well. almost all of them.
The last of them was Cardinal Spada.
At the end of his life. he took refuge
on the Isle of Monte Cristo.
He had enough time to train one last knight.
A young man named Giuseppe Faria.
I'm the last one left. Edmond.
And I know where the treasure is.
Half of it is yours now.
But what will you do with all this wealth?
Will you do good?
Or will you let your heart
be overcome with hate?
I'll go empty the bag.
Edmond.
It's salty. The water is salty.
We're almost there.
It's just a matter of days.
We're almost there!
I'll be right back.
Come back. Abbot. come back!
Abbot?
Abbot? Abbot!
- There.
- Edmond--
No. don't talk.
I'll call for help. I'll call--
No. It's too late.
Don't be sad.
You have been the only solace in my life.
God sent you to me.
Maybe a little late.
I'm not crazy.
I know.
The treasure is real.
You know where to find it.
- We can look for it together.
- Don't-- don't forget.
Monte Cristo!
Monte Cristo...
Abbot. Abbot!
Abbot!
Don't leave me.
Don't leave me!
- Alive?
- Alive.
Alive?
Number 17.
Hey. 17!
Abbot?
Hey. Abbot?
Hey! He's dead! Throw me a bag.
- Who is it?
- The Abbot.
Alive?
Alive.
Come on. get up. Get up!
I said. get up!
On alert!
- One...
- On alert!
...two...
Alert!
...and three!
Hey! You have no business being here!
Leave at once!
I came to see Louis.
Louis Dantés.
You knew Louis?
Yes.
We buried poor old Louis.
A long time ago. my boy.
No. it can't be.
He starved himself to death
after his son died.
He wanted to be with him again.
But his...
His son isn't dead.
I'm sorry.
Were you a sailor too?
Yes.
I'll feed you. but after that. you're off.
Mercéd--
Mercédés and Fernand de Morcerf.
It's been seven or eight years
since they last came.
They've been living in Paris
since their son was born.
You're too late.
Avoid the Ligurian Sea.
with its relentless patrols.
Set a course for Sardinia.
You can make port
at Santa Teresa di Gallura.
The Isle of Monte Cristo lies
to the west of the Tuscan Archipelago.
You'll land at the southern tip.
I know you'll be overwhelmed
by its austere beauty.
I envy you for seeing it for the first time.
There it is.
The burial plot of the famous De Spada family.
The rest. Edmond...
...Is your story.
The story of a man who has
the whole world in the palm of his hand.
- Come on. I'll pay you tomorrow.
- No.
Mr. Caderousse is my friend.
On his deathbed.
Edmond Dantés asked me to share it
with the people he cared about.
He believed he'd been turned in
by a man named Danglars.
But he was convinced there were
two men who remained loyal to him.
He told me that one of them
was Gaspard Caderousse.
and the other was Fernand de Morcerf.
You can keep your diamond.
None of us deserve anything.
Wait. my son.
If I tell you what I know.
everyone will know it came from me.
And these people are rich and powerful.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'm bound by the Seal of Confession.
Please. sit.
Dantés was right about Danglars.
He's the one who reported him.
But Fernand de Morcerf... was his friend.
He was in love with his fiancée.
For Mercédés' sake. he sacrificed Edmond.
He'll live. But he'll be dead to the world.
The only one who deserves
Dantés' affection is Morrel.
The ship owner.
He's the only one
who fought to get him released.
But he too was given little thanks.
After Dantés' arrest.
he had no choice but to bring
Danglars back as captain.
But Danglars also betrayed him.
He made half his fleet disappear.
Said it was stolen by pirates.
Ruined. Morrel had to sell the company.
And guess who bought it back for pennies?
Danglars.
Two months later.
the boats reappeared miraculously.
The prosecutor. Villefort. didn't do a thing.
Well. both of them shared a secret.
Victoria. Villefort's mistress.
she had become Mrs. Danglars.
She's a baroness now.
Morrel died a poor man.
And what about you. Mr. Caderousse?
You...
What was I to do...
against a captain. a count. and a prosecutor?
If I had been braver.
I probably would have ended up like her.
Her?
Angéle.
She went to see her brother.
hoping to save Dantes.
I got rid of Dantés for you.
now you get rid of her.
See? I have friends too.
What happened?
Was she killed?
She would have suffered less.
But Danglars had other plans for her.
He sold her to the Maillard brothers.
the masters of the brothel of Toulon.
The girl was pretty.
he got a good price for her.
You knew everything and did nothing.
I'm ashamed. Father.
One day. I'll come back and give you
a chance to redeem yourself.
I no longer come to pray for you
or to find you.
but only to warn you.
I'm going to do what you couldn't.
From now on.
I will reward and I will punish.
Can I do anything for you. sir?
Who are you?
Years ago. you told me...
..."I won't forget your courage.
but you must forget my name."
Well. I haven't forgotten your name
or your courage.
Dantés.
I've come to save you. Angéle.
It's too late for me.
But you can save the child.
The child?
When I first arrived here...
...there was only one thing on my mind.
I wanted revenge on my brother.
For weeks.
I tried to find a way to escape.
One day. the opportunity presented itself.
I ran away.
With a client.
A Parisian draper.
I knew Gérard was appointed there.
I tracked down Victoria. his mistress.
I wanted to pick up
where the story left off.
It was freezing cold.
That night. Gérard was supposed to die.
Nothing could stop me.
I can still feel the knife in my hand.
But nothing went as planned.
I heard a scream. Victoria's scream.
When Gérard went out into the garden.
he was carrying a chest.
I followed him.
! moved closer. and I heard
the muffled screams of a baby.
I couldn't leave him.
He still had his mother's blood on his body.
Between revenge and life...
...I chose life.
I ran away with him.
I didn't know anyone in Paris.
So. I went back to my draper.
But the Maillard brothers had found him...
...and were waiting for me.
Angéle...
...what happened to the baby?
Hello. André.
- Angéle asked me to come and get you.
- Why?
She's dying.
I'll take you to her so you can say goodbye.
And then we'll leave.
We'll take all the time we need to be ready.
Ready for what?
Revenge. André.
To take revenge on the three men
who stole her life.
yours. and mine.
I want to kill them.
That would be too easy. Too merciful.
No.
We must cut out their hearts.
Who are you?
I'm the Count of Monte Cristo.
Today. the General de Morcerf
has decided to leave the army
and dedicate his life to politics.
to the Chamber of Peers.
The French army is losing a great soldier.
but France is gaining a great man.
Fernand de Morcerf fought at the Moskva River.
in Leipzig. in Turkey.
Everywhere. at great risk to his life.
he defended the kingdom of France.
Fernand paid in his own flesh
the price of his pledge
and the honor of his word.
Ten years ago. when France's ally.
Ali Pasha of Yanina.
was under siege from Turkish troops.
Colonel de Morcerf went all out.
At the head of a squadron of valiant soldiers.
he broke through the Ottomans' lines
to lend a hand to his ally.
Unfortunately. this act
of foolish courage wasn't enough...
...but as every Frenchman knows.
we don't fight in hopes of success.
no. it's much more beautiful when it's hopeless.
Better now?
You weren't very considerate
with Eugenie Danglars.
Father--
She'll have a dowry of two million
on her wedding day.
- Fernand!
- So it's not Eugénie
I have to worry about so much as her fortune.
Believe me. it's better to have
one less medal and one more zero.
Our son is a man of his time.
He's a romantic who believes--
Take the medal.
Enough.
Gentlemen. had I known of your visit.
I would have prepared myself for it.
Stop! Get out!
Gentlemen...
...had I known of your visit.
I would have prepared myself.
I'm sorry to welcome you in a makeshift home.
I've only been in France for a few weeks.
I'm sorry to bother you at home.
but our family can't thank you enough
for saving Albert's life.
The way he fought. I'm sure
he would have done the same for me.
Count. I owe you my life.
I'm glad to see you
on your feet again. young man.
I had it fixed. The handle was cracked.
Well. it's yours now.
I'm very grateful. Count. but I can't accept it.
I'm already in your debt
and I don't know how to repay you.
Do you like guns?
Please. follow me.
That's one of my finest pieces.
An Ottoman-style pistol.
The iron under guard on this cannon.
decorated with foliage.
means it was made in Europe.
It was made in Venice.
You're quite the connoisseur.
My father fought against
Sultan Curci with Ali Pasha.
Morcerf.
You are the famous General de Morcerf.
I'm very impressed.
Would you do me the honor of trying it?
Unfortunately.
I have to get back to the Chamber.
- But some other time. I'd be happy to.
- It won't take long.
You've earned your reputation. General.
We'll have to change the target for you. Albert.
Remind me never to challenge you to a duel.
I appreciate you leaving your son
with me for a few hours.
I can't wait to find out more
about the man fate has placed in my path.
I'm taking part
in Baron Danglars' hunt on Sunday.
Why don't you join us?
I'd love to. but I can't.
I must greet the son of Prince Cavalcanti.
Why don't you both come?
There will be enough stags for everyone.
See you soon.
See you Sunday. I hope.
Is everything alright?
My Ottoman adventure left me
with a small metal memento.
You prefer singing to weapons?
Follow me.
I beg your pardon. Count.
I meant no disrespect to your wife.
Haydée isn't my wife.
She's my goddaughter.
After you.
Haydée.
What a wonderful name.
It's a pretty common name in Greece.
It could be translated
as "modesty" or "innocence."
May I ask you to introduce me to Haydée?
You seem like a very trustworthy young man.
I'll introduce you.
But before I do so.
you must promise me something.
I'll do it now.
I'm not joking.
You must never try to seduce her.
So you think I'm dangerous?
No.
But she is.
If you don't keep your promise.
she'll break your heart. and hers.
But she's not ready to love yet.
The secret of her enchanting voice
lies in her past.
After her father was murdered.
she was sold to a Viach tribe from the Balkans.
That's when I met her and took her in.
You know. some sorrows
and wounds take years to heal.
They leave a veil over our souls.
Don't ever try to lift that veil. Albert.
I promise.
Good.
You'll walk softly.
and never give us so much as a glance.
Turn only when I call for you.
Haydée.
Albert de Morcerf.
- may I introduce Haydée.
- Pleasure to meet you. sir.
Pleasure to meet you. sir.
It's a pleasure to meet you. miss.
And if he doesn't want to meet me?
He will.
Sit up straight! From now on.
sitting up straight is survival.
Making it look like
you didn't grow up poor is survival.
Do you understand why? Why is that. André?
Because I am Prince Andrea Cavalcanti.
Doesn't Cavalcanti mean goat in Spanish?
- What?
- Don't look so surprised. "What?"
Do you hear me saying "what"? Start over.
I'm Prince Andrea Cavalcanti.
But you don't have an accent. Prince.
how come?
I had a very strict teacher
who beat my accent out of me.
That's rude. Your elbows.
Dear Count. it's a pleasure to meet you.
Let me tell you something.
I'm still completely unfamiliar with French life.
So. please forgive me in advance if my manners
may seem too Slavic. Neapolitan. or Arab.
My friends. may I present
the Count of Monte Cristo
and Prince Andrea Cavalcanti.
- Gentlemen.
- Count.
Prince.
Meeting your father. as upsetting as it may be.
can't distract you from your goal.
Baron Danglars made his fortune
in the slave trade
thanks to the ships he stole from Morrel.
Your reputation precedes you. Count.
Don't be fooled by his smile. He's brutal.
And he not only knows it. he takes pride in it.
May I make a confession?
I'm still completely unfamiliar with French life.
So. please forgive me in advance
if my manners seem
too Slavic. Neapolitan. or Arab.
When you're rich.
you can never be too much of anything.
- His weakness is his daughter.
- Prince.
- Baron.
- Eugénie.
- The playground isn't so bad.
- It's perfect.
Then let's go. Mount up. gentlemen.
Do us the honors. Count.
I'm grateful. Baron.
but I took an oath a long time ago.
I only kill in self-defense.
Please let me defend you. Count.
Very well.
Prince.
You do the honors.
Let's have lunch.
Eugénie.
Thank you. Suzanne.
this is Prince Andrea Cavalcanti.
the Count of Monte Cristo's Italian protégé.
He watches over me.
My father fears Paris' beauties
might make me act foolishly.
Your French is impeccable.
That's because I had a strict teacher.
he beat my accent out of me.
- That's terrible!
- I'm just kidding.
- My mother's French.
- What an idiot.
I'm so glad you could join us.
Your protégé's hand didn't shake.
The animal didn't even suffer.
And he's an expert on executions.
Do you often carry out executions?
Oh. much less than before. Count!
- Forgiveness is in fashion.
- Dear friends. excuse the interruption.
but I must introduce someone to the Count.
- Count.
- Gentlemen.
Yes. it's incredible.
Darling. I'd like you to meet
the Count of Monte Cristo.
Madame de Morcerf.
It's a pleasure.
Is everything all right. Mother?
Yes. it's...
I'm moved to meet the man
who has spared me from tears.
Sir. I owe you my son's life.
And for that. I bless you.
Madam. you're rewarding me
too generously for a simple action.
But I'm glad I saved you the grief.
I've invited the Count to be our guest.
but he has always declined.
Perhaps you'll have better luck than I did.
Would you do me the pleasure
and honor of one day being our guest?
Why. certainly. madam.
Please excuse me.
I'd hate to take up any more of your time.
What's the matter?
- Do you want me to call someone?
- Albert.
What do you know about him?
Mother.
I know you're always suspicious
of my new acquaintances.
but the Count saved my life.
He's as rich as a king.
Why would I fear him?
You're right. My fears are unfounded.
Mr. King's Prosecutor. it is on my honor.
as Lieutenant of the Royal Armies.
that I hereby attest
that the man named Edmond Dantés
has testified in my presence
and on numerous occasions to his sympathy
for the usurper and his desire
to one day take up arms
to overthrow the monarchy.
These words weigh heavily on me
for Edmond Dantes was my friend.
but now I cannot let this crime go unpunished.
I've seen too many men die
at the hands of traitors to the nation.
That's not how you fall asleep. Count.
I don't even want to sleep.
Are you afraid of nightmares?
I'm afraid I won't have them anymore.
They help me keep my wounds open.
Did you see her again?
Yes.
Was she as beautiful as you remember?
I thought grief might have changed her.
It must have been short-lived.
Her eyes were not those
of a woman who had cried too much.
She will become acquainted with tears
once we take her husband.
I pass.
I raise. 200 plus 500.
I give up.
I wouldn't invite you to my table
if you knew how to play.
Voila. There are only three of us left. gentlemen.
I'll leave you two alone.
Two pairs.
Bravo.
Flush.
You have too much heart for me. Baron.
I'm running away before I ruin my father.
Come. Albert.
Yes. that's it! Why don't you go see the ladies?
Unlucky at cards. lucky in love!
I'm fond of your prince. he's charming.
I hardly know him. to be honest.
His father is a business acquaintance.
A good family. no doubt.
If by good you mean rich. then yes.
he's the second richest man in Italy.
Second richest?
You know the richest. I presume?
Don't make me say something immodest.
Finally. someone richer than me.
His family dreams of him marrying a girl in Paris.
but if the son is as fickle as the father. beware.
Don't worry.
I'm wary of everyone in general and...
...especially of foreigners.
I'm a foreigner myself.
You don't count. Count.
And you're a count. And it rhymes.
You're a poet.
Speaking of foreigners. the newspaper
The Independent was sold to an Englishman.
Yes. a man named Halifax. a lord. I'm told.
Lord Halifax only buys newspapers
to spread fake news
and speculate on the stock market.
He's a brigand of the worst kind.
You don't seem to like this Lord very much--
Well. let's just say I like a lot of people.
but I only hate certain people.
Well. hating an Englishman isn't a sin.
it's common sense.
- Leaving so soon?
- It's almost midnight.
Our carriage will turn into a pumpkin.
Albert.
Miss. you almost forgot your fan.
Thank you. sir.
I'm counting on you.
For what?
To join me in a dinner party
I'm hosting soon in Paris.
I've finally got a place to stay.
Of. of course.
Good.
See you soon.
Count?
Madame de Morcerf.
- You're leaving as I arrive.
- Don't read anything into it.
I just wanted to apologize.
For what?
For my dizziness the other day.
You reminded me of someone
I knew well a long time ago
who disappeared
under tragic circumstances.
For a moment. I...
See. it's happening again.
I'm at a loss for words.
I'm the one who's sorry. ma'am.
for bringing up such a bad memory.
Don't worry. it's gone now.
I'm glad.
I bid you good evening. madam.
Count.
It's from Albert.
"Haydée. I'm not supposed to write to you.
That's why I'm not writing to you.
I'm not supposed to meet you..."
...that's why I'm not suggesting
that we meet in the Garden
at 5:00 p.m. tomorrow.
This place where I won't be tomorrow
houses the most mysterious flowers in Paris.
You're from a country we call
“the land of clouds and jasmine."
We can trust Paris for the clouds.
I'll have jasmine in my boutonniere.
So I won't say. "See you tomorrow.”
And I won't tell you that ever since I saw you.
I can't get your voice
or your face out of my head.
Albert.
- He's not going to report us?
- He's very loyal to the Count.
But I think he likes me.
It's a Strelitzia.
Where I come from. there were some
on a path leading to the sea.
It's also known as the bird of paradise.
Bird of paradise.
Bird of paradise?
Good.
How come you don't have a fiancée?
Or perhaps you do.
My father would like me
to marry a baron's daughter. but I...
...I'm looking for something
this lady will never have.
It's this indefinite charm
that is to a woman
what perfume is to a flower.
Or what flavor is to fruit.
I don't know if Parisian girls
like to be picked or eaten. but I don't.
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean it like that.
- I'm teasing you.
Will you be at
the Count's dinner on Saturday?
No. I'll be my mother's alibi.
She shuns social gatherings like the plague.
What about you?
I don't know your mother.
I don't know what she likes.
but I share her dislikes.
Neither he nor his mother
will be coming to dinner.
But Fernand de Morcerf will be there.
What's wrong?
Aren't you gonna tell me about Albert?
There is nothing to tell.
It's normal to have doubts.
To be afraid. I understand that.
But when the time comes. you must remember--
I don't need you to remind me
what his father did to mine.
He couldn't help but put his lips on it.
- Thank you.
- Watch your step.
My dear friends.
Good evening. Victoria.
I was also expecting
something more spectacular.
You don't have to make that face.
Count on the Count to have
some surprises in store for us inside.
You don't have much of an appetite.
Mr. de Villefort.
Well. I had an appetite
before the pork and the fowl.
This is...
- ...a beautiful house.
- I sense you're surprised. Baron.
Nothing gets past you. Count.
To be honest. I thought a man like you
would choose a more central part of town.
like the Champs-Elysées or St. Germain.
Well. I bought this house
because I was advised not to.
Why is that?
Well. it's said to be haunted.
They say a heinous crime
was committed here years ago.
Beware. we have with us the King's Prosecutor.
It's true.
They say a child was sacrificed.
- That's terrible!
- And you bought the house anyway.
And you did the right thing.
All these ridiculous ghost stories
are made up by malicious servants.
- Or jealous neighbors.
- You're wrong. Prosecutor.
I've lived in Asia and India.
it's hard to return from these trips
without realizing that there's
an invisible world populated by spirits.
When I first visited this house. I...
...I knew right away.
I had a strange feeling that a crime
had indeed been committed here.
So. I asked to be left alone for the night.
But weren't you afraid?
If your conscience is pure.
ghosts don't haunt you.
- They speak to you.
- And what did they tell you?
Yes. what did they say?
That night. I settled down here.
right in front of this fireplace.
I smoked some opium to be more receptive.
There's nothing like it to broaden
the spectrum of your consciousness.
In the sweetness of the smoke...
...I felt like I was floating.
I heard a bang in the wall.
Followed by another.
I laid my hand on the wall
and I heard screams coming from upstairs.
I climbed the stairs.
The screams turned into groans.
They were coming from a room
at the end of the hall.
I opened the door and found myself in a room.
In the middle. there was a bed.
I put my hand there.
I saw a woman writhing in pain.
She was given birth to a child.
She was alone. Abandoned.
Screaming.
And that's when I felt
a presence behind my back.
Suddenly...
You're scaring the ladies. Count.
And delighting us.
Go on. Count. I beseech you!
Pull yourself together. dear.
You're spoiling the fun.
I turned around. trembling.
And then I heard a whisper in my ear.
It was a child's voice.
A child's voice begging me to set him free.
I found a door.
A back door I hadn't seen in the dark.
I opened it. there were stairs.
They led to the garden.
And that's when I heard it again.
the child's voice.
He told me he'd been alone for so long.
He was crying.
He was crying out for his mother.
I searched all night. but...
...the garden was too big.
So. what did you do?
I'm sorry?
The garden was too big.
What did you do?
Oh. right.
Well. the next morning.
we started digging... everywhere.
We ripped out the apple trees.
dug up the trail. but nothing.
So. I brought a truffle pig from Périgord.
And?
Since he didn't find anything either...
...we ate him tonight.
Wonderful!
I told you it was all a fairy tale.
A fairy tale. Exactly.
Or so I thought... until yesterday.
As we were planting the torches
in the ground for tonight's reception.
one of them snapped in two.
So we dug around there and...
...we found a chest.
And?
What was in it?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean. you don't know?
Well. I waited for you to open it.
What if there's a body inside?
We'll give him a proper burial.
Prosecutor. perhaps you'd like to open it?
- I beg you. don't open it.
- Victoria. stop it!
Abracadabra.
I don't know how much of this is true.
but you are a magician. Count.
How is it possible? It's like he was there!
All those details were--
- I thought I'd go mad.
- Please. calm down.
- Where is our child's body?
- I don't know.
- You left it there. didn't you?
- Yes.
- You told me he was dead.
- Of course he was dead.
- Then where is he?
- I don't know. dear.
- Where is our child?
- I don't know!
Calm down. you're hysterical! I don't know.
Calm down.
I do know one thing.
Before a week goes by.
I'll find out who this Monte Cristo is.
Where he's from. where he's going.
and why he talks
about buried children in front of us.
Danglars is only suspicious of people
who are after his money.
Morcerf trusts me blindly
ever since I saved his son's life.
Only Villefort is left. Villefort is a prosecutor.
He's a wary man.
After this dinner.
Victoria will demand an explanation.
So. to reassure her and to reassure himself.
he will investigate.
And since we always learn so much more
from ill-intentioned mouths.
he'll go to the Count's sworn enemy.
Lord Halifax.
What do you want to know?
If there's anything I can do to hurt him.
it will be my pleasure.
Has the Count ever been to Paris?
He says he hasn't.
If he'd been here before. I'd know.
In that case. do you know
where he was 15 years ago?
Yes. in India.
But I must say...
...at the time. I still found him amusing.
But then...
Then what?
One night. I was correcting
a servant who had it coming.
But Monte Cristo had a passion
for those savages.
with their pagan god and their absurd magic.
Ridiculous beliefs. you know!
Then. he challenged me to a duel.
- For an indigenous person?
- Yes. an indigenous person.
Would you believe that?
Oh! It's hot. Aren't you hot? It's hot in here--
Can someone get me my fan.
for goodness' sake?
We're dying out here!
Not this--
Thank you.
And you. Mr. de Villefort?
- What did he do to you?
- Nothing.
I'm not sure yet if I should count him
as my friend or my enemy.
If he was your enemy. you would already know.
He's a lot of things.
but he's not one to hide his intentions.
But... be careful. Mr. Prosecutor.
If he becomes your friend.
that will make you my enemy.
Of course.
Yes!
Thank you. Mr. de Villefort.
It's been very nice chatting with you.
but I've got a lot of work to do.
Thank you. Lord Halifax.
Mr. Prosecutor.
Victor.
Yes. Count?
Get the horses ready.
we're going back to the castle.
Now that Villefort's guard is down.
we have plenty of time to prepare our attack.
I'm going south. I'll be back
for the party Danglars is organizing
for his daughter's 20th birthday.
During my journey. I'm counting on you.
André. to get closer to her.
And on you. Haydée. to bewitch Albert.
It can hold 600 slaves. 700 if you push a little.
But I'm a humanist.
I call it The Hercules.
My mom used to say all the time
that this is the line of people
who will do great things.
And this is your love line.
And here. I see that--
Andrea. I have to tell you something.
Yes?
I want to love you. but I can't.
I know.
I know you'll never be able to give me
that which you feel for Suzanne.
- It'll be our secret.
- Don't worry. it'll be our secret.
- I'll keep it well guarded.
- I know what it's like to play two roles.
I know what it's like to play two roles.
To not be able to be who you are.
I'll be your alibi.
It's time to redeem yourself.
I relive every second
of these moments with you in my dreams.
I'll take the memory of your eyes
with me into the night.
And I speak to no one because I don't want
to waste the echo of your words
that still tremble in my heart.
I keep your sheet music close to me.
I love it for how it makes me think of you.
but also. above all. I love it
for the memory it will bear forever.
That of a moment in life worth a lifetime.
- See you later.
Prince.
Eugénie. This party is just like you.
- lively and happy.
- Thank you. Andrea.
Will the Count of Monte Cristo
be among your guests this evening?
- Seventeen.
- Seventeen?
You're the 17th person to ask me that question.
And what have you told everybody?
There won't be an 18th.
There he is.
Excuse me.
Miss. Count.
- How was your trip?
- Splendid.
Thank you. Albert.
Eugénie is looking forward to seeing you. miss.
Count. may 1?
Of course.
Does the Count know we've been together?
I haven't told him.
Do you think he can figure it out?
God knows what he's capable of.
They're beautiful. aren't they?
They look so eager to live.
We're always in a hurry to be happy.
are we not?
Count. allow me the honor of your arm.
I feel like taking a walk.
Your hand is shaking.
You seem cold.
In my family.
we have cold hands. but warm hearts.
Here. this will warm us up.
Our grapes don't taste like your Sicily grapes.
but you'll be forgiving of our northern sun.
I apologize.
I apologize. madam. but... I never drink.
In that case. may I offer you something to eat?
I'm going to have to decline again.
Count.
There's an Arab custom
that creates eternal friendship for those
who share bread and salt under one roof.
I know that. madam.
But this is Paris. not Tangier.
In France. there are neither eternal friendships
nor the sharing of bread and salt.
But we are friends. aren't we?
Why. certainly.
Why wouldn't we?
Instead of bread and salt.
maybe you would like to share
some of your memories?
What do you wish to know. madam?
Is it true that you have seen much.
and traveled. and suffered?
What makes you say that?
Your eyes.
They say every great traveler
is searching for something
or running from something.
And have you found it?
I haven't finished my journey.
You live alone.
I have no sister. no son. no father.
I only have Haydée.
who I'm sure will leave me soon.
How can you live like this.
with nothing to hold on to?
I was in love with a young woman.
I was going to marry her.
Years ago.
But when the war came.
it took me away from her.
I thought she loved me enough to wait for me.
To remain faithful to me until the grave.
But when I came back...
...she was married.
Maybe my heart was more fragile...
...but I've endured more suffering.
- That's my story.
- And that love stayed with you?
You only really love once.
Right?
Did you ever see this woman again?
Never.
Never?
Did you ever forgive her
for what she did to you?
We can only forgive those
who ask for our forgiveness.
What if she asked for it today?
Buy The Independent!
Danglars' fleet stolen from Marseille!
Buy The Independent. ladies and gentlemen.
The Independent!
How can someone steal boats
from a harbor in broad daylight?
- Were they insured?
- What do you think?
Danglars' stock is plummeting
in the stock market.
But thanks to the Army telegraph.
Danglars will learn before anybody else
that nothing happened in Marseille.
Weren't you supposed to steal those boats?
- Good things come to those who wait.
- You're saved.
Your boats are still there.
- What?
- The Independent lied.
"Danglars" fleet
is still docked at Marseille Harbor."
Thank you! Thank you. friends!
Danglars will remember
what I told him. and he'll think--
That's a move from the new boss
of The Independent. our dear Lord Halifax.
That's right.
Monte Cristo was right.
That English pig is using his newspaper
to speculate about me.
We must issue a denial.
- Absolutely not.
- I don't understand. You have to--
Do you hear that?
Listen.
What a lovely sound.
A lovely little sound.
The sound of money falling.
- I don't understand.
- Think.
He knows something no one else knows yet.
Imagine you're playing poker
and you know your opponent's hand.
- What do you do?
- I raise.
The stocks are at an all-time low.
If I buy them. in two days
I'll have made an extraordinary profit.
My finest move.
Buy back your shares?
How much would it cost?
- Five hundred million! Yes.
- Five hundred million?
But it has to be done today.
Before the market closes.
and before that bastard Halifax does it.
How are you going
to get 500 million by tonight?
By going to Lord Halifax's greatest enemy.
I'm sorry. Baron. but...
...the sea has always brought me bad luck.
- I won't buy back your shares.
- Count--
However. I never refuse to help
a friend and punish an enemy.
So I'll lend you the money.
and you can do whatever you want with it.
I can guarantee you a 20% interest rate.
No. I'll lend you the money interest-free.
There's a saying in Sicily.
"You don't get rich off a friend."
I insist.
I've had a mortgage drawn up
on my entire estate.
It's not 500 million. just 200 million.
- I can promise you that.
- Your word is good enough for me.
You know. in France. we say.
"Good accounts make good friends."
So be it. Then. as a friend.
I accept your personal guarantee.
In a week. I'll pay you back.
We're going to bring this Halifax to his knees.
A complaint is ready.
I'll take care of the claim myself.
Well. I'm looking forward to being
in court to witness this execution.
Lord Halifax. owner of The Independent.
who was called to the stand today
to answer defamation charges.
had to leave the country in a hurry.
But he pledges to have his representative
present at this court at 2:00.
Your Honor. the charade
has gone on long enough.
We are not here to play games.
I request Mr. Halifax's representative
to come forward if he is present.
What are you doing? It's not over yet.
I'm Lord Halifax's representative.
I stand before you because
The Independent has been accused
of spreading fake news.
I stand before you today...
...to say that Danglars' fleet is. in fact. gone.
Nonsense! My entire fleet is in Marseille!
Your Honor. this is a farce.
What proof do you have?
You must simply contact
the harbormaster of Marseille. Your Honor.
Then. you persist in your assertions?
I persist and sign. Your Honor.
But I would like to do so under my real name.
You have a fake one?
Everyone knows me as Andrea Cavalcanti.
After years on the streets.
I was taken in by a distinguished
and wealthy noble Italian family.
I grew up as a thief and ended up as a prince.
My new job isn't more honest than my last.
but it's much more enjoyable.
It was here in Paris that I was
finally able to trace my real father.
I was born on November 3rd. 1815.
In Auteuil.
Your Honor. can...
...the defendant...
present evidence to support his claim?
I'm coming to that. Mr. Prosecutor.
Believe me. your patience will be rewarded.
I am the bastard son
of a French aristocrat and his mistress!
My mother doesn't know I'm alive.
since my father told her I died at birth.
He wrapped me in cloth and buried me alive.
You speak. sir. of attempted infanticide.
It would've been the case...
...if my aunt hadn't heard my cries
and dug me out of the ground.
Who are you accusing?
A respectable man
that you all know.
His coat of arms is on this linen.
My father. the man who tried to kill me.
is none other than the man before me.
Prosecutor Villefort.
Quiet or I'll clear the court!
This is slander!
- I'll sue you!
- Mr. Cavalcanti.
Are you aware
of the magnitude of your accusations?
I warn you. I won't settle for a cloth.
even with blood on it.
The prosecutor will bring you
the proof of my claim himself.
- You're delirious.
- Father.
Please. don't make my mother testify.
She's been through enough already.
The trial is on hold until further investigation.
Everyone. leave the room!
One down.
Come on. Victoria. let's go!
Sorry! Let us through.
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
Your father wanted me
to be his son-in-law but...
...it's impossible because
we have the same mother.
Don't forget your lifeline. Be happy. Sister.
Count. Count!
This story doesn't make any sense.
It's complete madness.
My boats were still in Marseille yesterday. I--
I'm going to need
a little more time to pay you back.
You have nothing left. Baron.
Everything that was yours is now mine.
All you have left are the clothes on your back.
Leave Paris at once and maybe
I won't let your wife and daughter starve.
Come on. Count.
You think I'm harsh. Baron?
I know I am.
I take pride in that.
You should take your wife home.
She looks quite pale.
Two down.
Father!
A gift from Angéle!
- Out of the way!
- No!
Why. André?
Why?
Don't cry.
I knew it would end like this.
- I knew it.
- Haydée.
He didn't listen.
He didn't listen?
What didn't he listen to?
You taught him nothing but hate.
You're the one who put that dagger in his hand.
Only your grief speaks?
I loved him like a son.
Do you love me too?
Are you also willing
to sacrifice me for your revenge?
It's not revenge.
It's justice.
Remember your tears. Haydée!
Your mother's screams and your father's blood.
Do not forget the name
of the one who betrayed them.
Remember his name!
“If you love me as I love you.
don't ever come looking for me.
You're too noble-hearted to not understand me.
I save my strength to fight
against myself and drink my tears.
Be happy far from me. You deserve it."
Albert?
Albert.
Are you mad? You can't stay here.
Haydée. I've only known you a few months--
Leave.
Run from me like you run from the plague.
- I'll make you miserable.
- Run away with me.
I swear to you. Haydée.
I promise you happiness. not despair.
You don't know me.
You don't know the Count.
- Haydée--
- If you love me as I love you...
...say goodbye.
I beg you.
Say it!
I'll say it.
I vow before God. from the depths of my heart.
I wish you a life happy enough
to leave no room for memories of me.
Goodbye. my love.
Those. those eyes--
Without you. my life is meaningless.
My despair is guaranteed.
What are you going to do?
Don't worry. I'll keep my promise.
But for heaven's sake. you'll live. won't you?
What do you care?
Since I'm already dead to you.
Let's elope.
Haydée. If you wish to join the Morcerf family...
...I think Albert deserves to know your story.
If you remain silent.
I shall be forced to refuse or speak for you.
Do I really need to speak for you?
Count. please!
- Haydée is the daughter of--
- Stop!
I'll tell him myself.
My father was a famous man...
...known as Ali Tepelini.
Pasha of Yanina.
I was ten years old...
...when he was killed
in front of me and my mother.
He had welcomed a French soldier...
...who was our ally.
Shot by a dozen bullets...
...my father found
the strength to stand up.
And he shot the man who betrayed him.
He took out one of his eyes.
I never saw my mother again.
That officer sold me as a slave
to a Viach tribe from the Balkans.
- His name was--
- Enough.
Albert...
- You manipulated me from the beginning.
- I warned you.
- You used me.
- Don't say words you can't take back.
- Do you think I'm afraid of you?
- For the last time. stop provoking me.
- Albert. please-- Count!
- You've taken everything from me.
All I have left is my name.
and you've tarnished it.
No!
Count. I beg you!
Sir. I'll take your glove.
I'll give it back first thing
in the morning. with a bullet.
- Have you no mercy?
- Did they show mercy for Edmond Dantés?
Look at me.
I am nothing more than the agent
of fate's deaf and blind will.
And Fernand de Morcerf
will know what my father knew.
If you kill Albert...
...you won't be able to say. "God is mine.
God is with me."
You'll be a murderer.
It is written in the Bible that the sons
will pay for the crimes of their fathers.
Jacopo. follow her.
Jacopo. leave us.
Madam...
...what are you doing here?
Edmond. you won't kill my son.
What name did you say?
Yours.
Edmond. it's not Mrs. de Morcerf
in front of you. it's Mercedes.
I don't know anyone by that name.
I recognized you the second I saw you.
and even if I hadn't.
I'd have recognized your voice.
My mind refused to believe. but my heart knew.
I've been watching you since that day.
trying to figure out your plan for Morcerf.
You mean Fernand. madam.
Since we remember each other's names.
let's remember them all.
I'm the guilty one.
I'm the one who lacked strength
in the face of your absence.
I'm the one who didn't have faith
when I heard you were dead. Me!
Why? Why were you alone?
Why wasn't I here? Why was I arrested?
- Why was I given a death sentence? Why?
- I don't know.
I don't think he still writes you love letters.
But I think you'll easily
recognize his handwriting.
Take a look.
Look. Mercédés.
This is what your husband wrote
to Villefort 20 years ago.
I must avenge myself. Mercédés.
I must.
Then avenge yourself. Edmond.
But take revenge on the guilty.
On Fernand. who betrayed you.
Take revenge on me. but spare Albert.
If only you knew all the prayers...
...if only you knew the tears I've shed.
Did you lose your father in loneliness?
Did you see the one you loved
in the arms of your rival?
Did you?
No.
But I see the man I never stopped loving...
...getting ready to murder my son.
What do you want. Mercédés?
Do you want your son to live?
He will.
Thank you.
Thank you. Edmond.
That's the man I know.
As I've always dreamed of you.
As I've always loved you.
But now it's time to say goodbye.
Goodbye?
If I give up on my revenge.
I give up on the only thing
that's keeping me alive.
The duel is tomorrow.
Goodbye. Mercédés.
Mr. Albert de Morcerf.
you have publicly provoked
the Count of Monte Cristo.
The duel will take place
at 20 paces on my command.
The insulted party goes first.
Take your positions.
Go on. gentlemen.
Fire!
Do I detect a glimmer
of disappointment in your eyes?
I will never forgive you for taking his life.
And for breaking my heart.
So you did love him.
If I loved him?
Everything pushed me to hate him.
but who can explain why we fall in love?
No matter how hard we try
to reason with ourselves. it's too late.
We've lost our balance.
Our inner voice whispers
that there are no coincidences.
And instead of listening to that voice.
I listened to yours!
I would have made his misery and mine!
What am I going to do
with all this love I haven't given him?
These words I haven't told him?
You have told him.
He heard them.
Albert.
Count!
Run now.
Run and don't let anyone steal your happiness.
Edmond!
Show yourself. Edmond!
I've been waiting for you.
You're finally showing your true colors.
And I've been seeking
to uncover yours. Fernand.
To know who you really are.
So I followed in your footsteps.
I've been everywhere you've been.
I've met them all.
Your friends. your comrades in arms.
your enemies. all of them.
Who didn't you betray. Fernand?
To whom have you remained loyal?
Everywhere you've shown your true colors.
I lost faith in man... the day you betrayed me.
You should have killed me.
It's never too late.
Get up.
Look at me. Look at me!
Kill me.
We see greatness in those who are gone...
...and eventually we forgive them.
I don't want you to be forgiven.
Mercédés.
I've come to say goodbye where life
took us away from each other
21 years ago today.
So many things were broken
in me and around me since then
that the man you knew is gone.
I promised to love you until I died.
and for a long time after that.
And I will always love you.
But it is no longer in my power
to give you happiness.
All I can offer you now is consolation.
Your son will be happy.
Albert and Haydée
will live out the story we couldn't.
Happiness to our children.
who will outlive us
and taste the sweetness of love.
As I write to you.
I'm living out my last moments with you.
Everything after it will be memories.
I will take them with me to the sea.
The one place on earth
where everything is horizon
and there are no traces left by men.
Live and be happy.
Never forget. until the day
when fate can bring us together again.
that all human wisdom is in these two words.
"waiting" and "hoping."
Edmond Dantés. The Count of Monte Cristo.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today